Welcome into a special next man up. It's
free agency Friday's here in the Big
Bear AI command center studio. We have
one of our newest commanders in the
building. Akeem Robinson in the
building. Looking good, looking happy my
brother. Congratulations man. Thank you
all man. Glad to be a part of great
organization man. I can't wait to do big
things with y'all. Yes sir man. Yes sir.
You've had a few stops during your time.
What made you say at this point in your
career that you want to come play for
Washington? Um you know a great
opportunity man. Young young secondary.
You know and and I can tell this
coaching staff you know they it's a
different between going to a place
you know just to whatever figure it out
but it's a it's a totally different
feeling also another crazy feeling going
to a place where you where you wanted.
You know when when the coaches and and
you know and GM and all of them like
they they believe in you. You know and
it makes you you know want to just
go that extra mile. You know so just
being a part of this organization man I
can't wait you know uh
I can't wait to just you know showcase
what I can do and uh why I'm the guy you
know why I'm why I'm here. You know just
can't wait to show
uh earn respect for my teammates. You
know and earn respect for my coaches cuz
like I said man this
it ain't given man it's earned. You know
so that's why I'm here. And you earned
it man. When when you talk to a guy like
DQ I know y'all the finish really love
talking to him cuz he's a defensive
minded guy. He's defense first. What has
conversation been like with DQ now that
you're in the building? Oh it was it was
kind of short and sweet I could tell.
Man most of the time he most of the time
the conversation you hug me for about
and hug me tight for about 10 minutes.
You know what He's got that family pop
uncle feeling for sure. So he you know
he just
you know he just told me like hey you
know we looking for energy. You know
just be you I'm going to allow you to be
you. You know so like I said when you
got a guy like that and he's crazy you
know my former coach told me the same
thing. You know I just you know just
just be you man. Be yourself that's what
makes makes you different you know so
just having a a head coach like that
and on top of that he going to come with
energy each and every day like I walked
in and it was playing my side. They were
playing my kind of music. You know what
I'm saying? So I said oh yeah I
definitely belong here. You know so I
can't wait I like I just it's just an
unreal feeling man. It's just an unreal
feeling. You said be me.
Who is Akeem Robinson? A a guy man. You
know first and foremost a very humble
guy man. A guy that love the game of
football. You know my play style shows
shows that. You know if I could I'd play
this game for free man. You know so it's
just it's just it's just it's just like
you know it's I'm you know I'm a guy
that's going to come to work hard
worker.
You know a guy that's going to let my
actions speak as well but like I said
like I said before not only you know I
want to do good for myself. You know I
will also want to help help my teammates
you know as well. You know even though
I'm going into to year seven I'm still
an open book man. You know I'm still you
know I'm still learning. You know
and whatever I learn I give back to the
younger guys you know as well. So
and last but not least man you guys
getting an unbelievable teammate. We
love [clears throat] that man. You're
coming into a building where we have a
brand new defensive coordinator in
Dorante Jones but he is known to be
somewhat of a secondary whisperer if you
will. How excited are you to see what
Dorante Jones can unlock out of Akeem
Robinson?
>> Very very like I'm I'm I'm very excited
man. You know very cuz you know I
watched him previous years you know from
the sideline. You know just watching his
guys out there
how they flying around the ball how they
how they getting those takeaways and
wishing that I you know man I wish I
could you know what I'm saying? So it's
like now that I'm
you know I'm in in that style of
defense. You know I like I said I just
can't wait to explode man. You know and
not only myself I know these young guys
you know they're going to do the same
thing as well. Watching you throughout
the years watching you find your way
onto that field being a late round pick
finding your way on that field being an
undersized guy. I watch you and I say oh
this kid got a chip on his shoulder. I
look at you tuning out a couple tweets
after you sign and I say this kid got a
chip on his shoulder man is that true?
Yeah oh it it never leaves. You know um
from from from from middle school to
high school it's always oh but but this.
Okay I I beat those odds. Get to college
oh he's not going to do it in college. I
did it in college. Oh but it's a smaller
school. Okay I did it in the league. Oh
but it's it's always but but that's okay
though. You know that's okay cuz like I
said I've been proving my proving it you
know my whole life but this time I'm not
proving it to nobody else. You know I'm
I'm I'm proving it to myself. You know
so like I said I you know I see it. You
know I see the media I see but
eventually the smoke always clear. You
know it it always clear. You know I just
like I said I and I'm not playing you
know for for whatever whatever. You know
I'm out there playing for myself and my
teammates you know and my coaches. And
we love that man. I can see the fire in
you and to be real you're one of the
shorter corners in the NFL but you don't
play like it. You you tackle. You make
plays man and I think when people look
at you they say oh this is the type of
player that Dorante Jones likes. He has
that versatility. We've seen you play on
the outside. We've seen you play in the
slot. Where is Akeem Robinson most
comfortable on the field? Uh I'm I'm I'm
a football player man. You know when
they ask me you know I just say I'm a
you know I'm a football player hybrid
whatever.
You know I always figure it out. I've
been figuring it out my whole life. You
know so it's
it's be it's became the norm. You know
just put me on the field man and let me
know where we in and okay and I'm going
to watch this watch tape and see what
what I could cheat on what I you know so
I'm I'm always going to figure it out
but most importantly
I'm going to I'm going to try to do
what's best for my you know for for my
teammates you know as well cuz like I
said I'm going to always figure it You
know so when they ask me uh you know
what you what you rather play it don't
matter to me. You know just just put me
on the field man make sure my cleats
tied man and you know you know I'm
ready. What inspires Akeem Robinson? Uh
probably probably you know I would say
of of course you know my son. You know I
you know always you know the moment I
held him man you know just gave me that
extra motivation. But um also just the
the love of the game man. Like
they don't understand like how much I
love this game. You know I've been
playing it since I was 5 years old the
moment my uncle put me in it. So it was
like
that's all I know is football. You know
high school when we had career day I had
the bands on and everybody was like nah
you need a you need a plan plan B. Nah
this this is my plan B. I've always knew
that I was going to be in the league
playing this game of football. If you
can look at my old posts from years ago
2014 15 like I've always knew I you know
I would be
playing at the you know the highest
because I cuz of the work ethic and just
you know believing my dream and the love
and passion that I have for this game
man. You know we all see how you know
how you know my style of play how how I
play. You know it's just that that's
just determination and love and passion
that I have for the game. And I love you
mentioned your son man because it's not
always promised to get a second
contract. It's not always promised to
get a third contract. You've been able
to share this journey with your son man.
How fly is that? Cuz I know I I have a
son of my own man and getting to share
different things with work it's like
there's nothing better than that.
>> Yeah I mean it's you know it it was it
was fly of course at the beginning but
he's getting so used to it now. He don't
realize how how dope that is. You know
what I'm saying? Like he understand how
dope it is. I remember we played a
couple years back at the Raiders man I
got a game when they pick him. I threw
the ball to him he cried. My first time
seeing him cry at at my game. You know
what I'm saying? It's like but now it's
like he's meeting all these other
players it's like
it's it's it's it's becoming a norm to
him you know but you know I got another
son he's he's two maybe you know it'll
it'll hit him you know later. You know
but for as my oldest man he you know
it's like I said it's becoming a norm
for him man. I just wish I was in his
situation in his position. I'm about to
say my bad. About to get some new shoes.
Oh I'm about to be coming pretty soon.
He's living good man. Living living
great. [laughter] Living great man. Well
Akeem you know you're a great dad. We've
seen that as you know you've gone
through your career and now you get a
chance to be big bro in this building
cuz you know we got some young guys
particularly Trey Amos and Mikey Sanders
where people look at Mikey and they say
undersized defensive back that plays
like he's 6'8 300 lbs. Very similar man.
How can you help this young secondary
room with all the things you've learned?
>> Keeping it genuine man. You know
something that [clears throat] I did at
you know same at the at at at Detroit I
built a great relationship with guys
that you know at Detroit. They know what
kind of guy I am. They know you know
what I bring to the table for as you
know when I'm at practice. You know they
know that whatever you know the love
that I have for the game I try to pour
them into those to those guys you know
extra work after practice. Try to you
know just try trying to be on the same
page you know cuz like I said before you
know I'm going to continue missing it
like
I I I don't only want success for myself
you know on the field because if I want
to do it by myself we won't win. You
know and you know
I also want success for those guys you
know and I think that's I think that's
that's my purpose on why I'm here. You
know um
of course get God giving me another
opportunity to play the game that I love
but also
you know giving back to those guys man
cuz I mean they're already dogs. You
know they're already dogs. You know but
it just you know me coming in
another dog another wolf just just
coming in kind of pouring that into them
and we all doing it together you know as
a as a unit and finding our identity.
You know so I just can't wait to get the
show on the road man. And you said
finding success. So what does success
look like for you in 2026? Winning.
Yeah. Winning man. Winning. Helping the
team win man. Being the best teammate.
Of course being better than what I was
It's always it's always levels you know
for myself being better than what I was
last year. You know of course you know
coming up with those INTs man. I dropped
too many last year. Too many.
Too many man but you know just just
being a better version of myself you
know helping this defense you know and
and and winning you helping the team win
you know helping this defense you know
get over that hump. Man we love that so
much and I love what you said about I'm
not here to prove nothing to nobody. But
you're here to prove something to
yourself. What are you trying to prove
to yourself? Just to like I said before
man just to
to prove that I belong. You know I know
that I belong but it's like I always
have to continue to do that each and
every each and every time. You know and
and also prove to myself man that that
that you can be one of you know the
all pro this
pro bowl that. You know but it also goes
into how you as a
as a teammate. You know you know
continue being a being a being a great
being a great teammate pouring that into
your to your teammates man. Like I said
I just can't like I said, I just can't
wait to get the show on the road, man. I
can't can't wait to suit up, pad up,
compete. It's
I don't know, bro. I just I just can't
wait. Man, well, you're well on your
way. Contract signed out, the money in
the bank account. So, now it's just time
to work. And Meek, and we're so excited
to have you as part of this team. Can't
wait to see how you fit in with this
secondary. And honestly, can't wait to
see what happens with you when Daronte
Jones gets his hands on you, bro. You
are the perfect defensive back for this
system. We're so excited for you, man.
Again, my brother, congratulations.
Welcome to the burgundy and gold. You
home now, my guy. For sure. Thank you
all, man. I appreciate y'all. Commanders
family, it's free agency Fridays here
with our newest defensive back, Ameer
Robertson. You're going to be hearing
that name a lot this year, baby.